Guide to the Gregory Corso Papers, 1980-1991
Department of Special Collections
Gregory Corso Papers,
1980-1991
Special Collections M0877
Corso, Gregory.
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1996.
Scope and Content
The Gregory Corso Archive includes manuscript notebooks, published materials and personal and professional ephemera of Gregory Corso. They are housed in 3 document boxes and occupy 1.5 linear feet. The materials are arranged in the following series:
Manuscript notebooks
Publications
Ephemera, letters and photographs
The collection covers Corso's work in the 1980s and early 1990s, including both manuscript notebooks and published works. The ephemera includes professional and personal correspondence with Allen Ginsberg as well as materials documenting Corso's public appearances and professional collaborations. The ephemera series also includes photographs of Corso. Most of the items in the collection are signed.
Access Terms
Coppola, Francis Ford.; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-; Kerouac, Jack, 1922-1969.; American literature--20th century.
Container List
- Series I. Manuscript notebooks, 1.5 linear ft.
  - Manuscript notebook, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript notebook, c. 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1988. NYC. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1988.Rome, Italy. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1988. Italy. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1988. NYC. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1988-1990. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1989. Paris. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1989. Rome, Italy. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1990. NYC. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1990. NYC. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript notebook, April 1992. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript notebook, Jan.- April 1992. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript notebook, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript notebook, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1985-1989. (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1987-1988. Rome and Cherry Valley, NY. (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1988. (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1989. Yellow legal pad. Includes cover art for Mindfield. (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript notebook, 1989-1990. (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript notebook, n.d. (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
  - 240 pages of manuscript poems and drawings. (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
- Series II. Publications, .5 linear ft.
  - Bombay Gin. No. 4, Summer-Fall 1977. Boulder, CO: Naropa Institute. Literary magazine. Cover photo of Corso. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Riverside Interviews 3: Gregory Corso. Ed. by Gavin Selerie with essays by Jim Burns and Michael Horovitz. London: Binnacle Press, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gregory Corso. Hitting the Big 5-0. NY: Catchword Papers, 1983. Signed copy. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gregory Corso. The Happy Birthday of Death. With "Bomb" as foldout. NY: New Directions, 1960. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Gregory Corso. The American Express. Paris: Olympia Press, 1961. The Traveler's Companion Series, no. 85. First edition. Signed copy. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gregory Corso. The Japanese Notebook Ox. Unmuzzled Ox, nos. 8/9, 1974. Signed copy, only edition published 1974. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gregory Corso. Mindfield, new & selected poems. NY: Thunder's Mouth Press, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gregory Corso. Mindfield, new & selected poems. Uncorrected proofs for review. NY: Thunder's Mouth Press. Signed copy. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Series III. Ephemera, letters and photographs, .5 linear ft.
  - 8 photographs. Includes: signed photograph of Corso and Allen Ginsberg in fully nude frontal pose; 3 signed photographs taken early 1980s; photograph taken by Francis Ford Coppola for Godfather III, signed by Corso and Coppola. (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript letters and ephemera. Includes: (Oversize 3, Folder 9)
    - 4 autograph postcards from Allen Ginsberg, 1990-1991.
    - 1 autograph note, Ginsberg to Corso, 1991.
    - Typed manuscript by Corso. 2 pages. Introduction to Dr. Sax by Kerouac. All writing and signatures by Corso. 1991.
    - 2 page autograph letter, Ginsberg to Corso, thanking him for introduction to photos.
  - 1 page autograph letter by Ginsberg to "Steven," his music consultant, about his book. (Oversize 3, Folder 10)
  - Printed broadside. "Freedom and the Poet's Responsibility to Society." Signed by Ginsberg. (Oversize 3, Folder 11)
  - "Bomba, bomb." Typed copy of "Bomb" in English and Italian. Signed. (Oversize 3, Folder 12)
  - Typed copy of "Meditation for Gregory Corso." Flyer for "Lowell Celebrates Kerouac 1989" - Corso and Diane DiPrima give poetry reading. (Oversize 3, Folder 13)